Software Engineer

Leal Williams

07490 417826

lealjwilliams@gmail.com https://lealwilliams.github.io/ linkedin.com/in/leal-williams-120783196 Sheffield Dinnington

About Me

I am a hardworking, competent Software Engineer who specialises in Games Programming. I have recently graduated from Sheffield Hallam University and was rewarded a 2:1 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science for Games. My most proficient languages include C++ and C#, with a lot of experience using Visual Studio in my projects. At University, I have experienced working with a small team on multiple projects, working together to meet tight deadlines. I have contributed ideas towards the implementation of the systems that make the programs function and taken feedback from my peers on how I could improve my own work. I also worked on multiple tasks simultaneously for my other modules.

Experience

Sheffield Hallam University - BSc - 2:1 - Computer Science for Games

2019-2022

- Attended regular scrum meetings with teammates and lecturers to discuss what goals we plan to achieve within the week and what we have accomplished in the last week.
- Updated my progress on Trello, showcasing how much time I have spent, and the total time left I
 predict I would spend on each task.
- Collaborated with Designers and Artists to realize their ideas into the project.
- Developed Games using an Object-Oriented Design, allowing the systems to efficiently be expanded with additional content.
- Contributed to Technical Design Documents detailing the systems I worked on.
- Experience in working on PS4 and PC games.
- Created a game by myself, using DirectXTK to create a 2D platformer using assets I created.
- Unity Group Project with a tight deadline of 6 weeks achieved.
- Worked on website development using HTML, CSS and .NET.

Aardvark Swift Recruitment - Work Experience

2018-2018

- Used Bullhorn to input and update information about clients
- Consulted with employees when an issue would arise
- 4-day work experience

Education

Sheffield Hallam University

2019-2022

• BSc - 2:1 - Computer Science for Games

Thomas Rotherham College

2017-2019

- Achieved 4 A Levels:
 - o Maths (A)
 - o Further Maths (B)
 - Computer Science (B)
 - o Physics (C)

Dinnington High School

2012-2017

Achieved 9 GSCEs, (A-C), including English
 (6), Maths (8) and Science (A)

Hobbies

- Game Development on Roblox
- Video Games
- Card Games

Key Skills

Software

- o Visual Studio
- Unity Engine 5
- Unreal Engine 4
- o GitHub
- o Autodesk 3DS Max
- o Microsoft Office Suite

Languages

- o C++
- o C#
- o Lua
- o Python
- o HTML
- o CSS
- .NET

References available on request